# Attila Győri

## Development Team Lead / Senior Software Development Engineer in Test

Seasoned, Software Development Engineer in Test with about 19+ years of experience in the field of Software Test Automation, Test Automation Framework development and test aiding software implementation. Proven ability in Back-end API Testing, Selenium WebDriver Automation Testing, TDD, BDD, Web testing and Functional testing. Experienced in each phase of Test Life Cycle (STLC) and good knowledge in all phases of SDLC. Leader of a Development Team (6-8 members) for 6 years





gyoriattila@yahoo.com







in www.linkedin.com/in/attila-gyori-ag



#### WORK EXPERIENCE



## Development Team Lead / Senior Java Test Automation Framework Developer Ericsson R&D. Budapest

November, 2016-present

- Support, lead and coordinate Java Test Automation framework Core Team (6 members)
- Planning and directing the work of software engineers / implement tasks: OpenALM, JIRA
- Defining new standards, best practices, processes
- Mentoring and coaching
- Support and follow annual performance goals
- Facilitating scrum activities: daily stand-up, grooming, planning, retro
- Managing and prioritizing Teams backlog in accordance with stakeholder needs
- Extended the portfolio of the team with Decision Supporting Dashboard Application for PMs, RVs and CI Team
- Organizing trainings
- Working with employees on career development plans
- Prioritization of development activities, and scoping out work with Product Owners / Test Architects
- Collect Know-how/ write confluence
- Participate/Drive architectural planning of Java Test Automation Framework
- Further development of Automation Framework and implementation of test tools
- Carry out proof of concept to find applicable approaches and technologies
- Introducing ReactJS integrated with Spring boot backend for Dashboard Application and providing knowledgeshare
- Introducing Cypress for front-end testing of Dashboard Application and providing knowledgeshare
- Implementing end-2-end features for Dashboard Application
- Code Reviewing
- Developing test activity supporting applications (such as gerrit review alert, grafana dasboard to pdf test report)
- Drive setting up full ci with precommit unit, embedded and real integration tests, static code analysis, review
- Integrating framework capabilities such as Selenium webdriver with container based Zalenium remote server

#### Senior Software Development Engineer in Test

#### Ericsson R&D. Budapest

September, 2015 - November, 2016

- Testing distributed SUT telecommunication network traffic analysis (big data)
- Java Test Automation Framework implementation
- Develop test structure, test run evaluation, result reporting, ci
- Form CI environment Jenkins, DSL, maven, gradle, sonar
- Support Test Framework lifecycle: versioning, branching git, quality gates, unit test coverage
- REST Api testing with RestTemplate and Rest Assured
- Test Case management: TestLink
- Test Case implementation using Jbehave and Cucumber
- Performance test development/maintenance/execution/evaluation: jmeter
- Additional internal test tool development: cluster lock, traceability matrix generator, etc.







# **Test Automation Engineer**

General Electric HealthCare. Budapest, Hungary

April, 2014 - September, 2015

- BDD automated test implementation for OSGI bundles- back end
- Feature file implementation for User Stories
- Rally tracking
- Test Automation Framework Development in Java
- Bundle and Service development for testing purposes
- Spring boot white box test implementation
- Jbehave test framework development
- Jbehave scenario writing

#### **GRAPHISOFT.**

#### Senior Quality Assurance Engineer (Automation Team, framework developer)

Graphisoft SE. Budapest, Hungary

January,2011–March,2014

- Impmeneting mysql based automated test runs result evaluating desktop application in Java
- Developing test case management tool in Java (with Perforce integration and XML based socket communication)

#### **Quality Assurance Engineer (Automation Team)**

Graphisoft SE. Budapest, Hungary

February, 2008 – January, 2011

- Active participation in QA and Development process design a planning
- Responsible for reviewing and revising automated test scripts written by the members of QA Department
- Providing technical support for other QA members as for automated test execution, evaluation, defect logging and reporting and especially optimizing automated test scripts
- Leader of the involvement of the manual tester department into QA Automated processes and automated script implementation
- Providing presentation upon the basics of programming in perl for the manual tester department
- Developed reporting and publishing system for automated test run results
- Managed and organized the initiation of an automated pre-filtering system (smoke-test)
- Supervising the pre-filtering system, reporting bugs, assuring the up-to-date state of the system, maintaining it

#### Junior Quality Assurance Engineer (Automation Team)

Graphisoft SE. Budapest, Hungary

January,2004–February,2008

- Expertise in Manual/Functional (regression) Automation Testing.
- Gained solid knowledge of Automation tools and Expertise in WinRunner (Test Automation Tool, C-like syntax)
- Designed and Implemented automated test script
- Developed small tools to facilitate automation framework
- Got acquainted with Perl programming at a higher level
- Deployed disk imaging for remote automated testing machines to facilitate a more standard testing environment and to allow installations on clean machines with significantly shorter preparation time
- Executed, evaluated and reported daily Automated Test Runs
- Got involved in process planning meetings

#### **Junior Quality Assurance Manual Tester**

Graphisoft SE. Budapest, Hungary

November, 2003 – January, 2004

- Detailed manual testing of software for the whole product lifecycle
- Designed and wrote test cases and workflow- like test scenarios
- Updated test cases in alignment with changing business requirements
- Maintained test environments including set up of test data, analysis and reports
- Reported, prioritized, tracked and retested test defects (Mercury Test Director) gained solid knowledge in development and process planning
- Participate in acceptance test (beta)
- Obtained high level knowledge of the company's main desktop software ArchiCAD



# HIGHLIGHTS OF ACCOMPLISHMENTS

- Integrating Selenium 4 to our (Ericsson EEA) test automation framework (UTF), using Zalenium docker container (2020-)
- Driving the introduction of verification pipelines in Jenkins CI pre-commit check: test coverage, sonar static analysis, review, commit size check, integration test, dry run, real integration test (2018-)
- Test Automation Team Lead (2016-):
  - Implementing java test automation framework core (using BDD & Spring) (it is called Unified Test Framework)
  - Coordinate group of 6 test framework developer
  - Conducting professional interviews (more than 8 candidate got employed and still at the project)
  - Project leader and lead programmer of test automation aiding desktop tools in java(2011-):
  - Test Case management tool Java SWT, XML, P4j, JUnit (2013-)
  - Test Result Evaluation Tool SWT, SQL, Java, RPC (2011-)
- Supervising and reviewing the adequacy of Automated test implementations, providing technical support and instructions (2010-)
- Leading project on involving the manual tester department into QA Automated processes and automated script implementation (2009-)
- Coordinated and designed a project upon setting up a pre-filtering automated system (Smoke Test) to decide if an ArchiCAD project is ready for detailed testing, involving and managing more than 20 QA member (2009-)
- Implemented defect collecting and reporting site in perl and PHP (2008-)
- Designed and developed a remote control application to reach remote machines under test (in Delphi) (2007-)
- Designed and developed UI providing tool for perl command line tools in Visual Basic (2007-).
- Participate as Automation Engineer in an experimental project on setting up random test sets via predefined atomic test cases (via a dependency graph)(2005-)
  - Got promoted from Manual Tester role within three months of employment to be Junior Test Automation Engineer

#### **PROFESSIONAL OBJECTIVES**

During my secondary school studies, I realized that the humanities are much closer to me than the science subjects. My choice, considering college, was much more conscious, regarding two aspects:

To improve my skills in computer science

To choose humanities which can be beneficial on the labour market, that is why I chose English as my second major besides computer science as an augmentation and "compensation" of the technical aspect of my skill set to remain a multilateral, versatile person.

During my college studies I met special psychology, broad psychology, didactics, and I was very interested in these subjects. I have always had an anthropocentric attitude. I always get in touch with anybody easily and efficiently. This recognition led me to the decision make a postgraduate degree in communication major. I also do a lot of coordinating and organizing functions in my present job as a Team Lead making a good use of these traits. I feel these skills to be a considerable advantage. I like to have a role which allows me to communicate and work with other people at an everyday basis while improving and broadening my technical knowledge, programming skills getting acquainted with up-to-date technologies, where I can utilize my organizing, management and creative skills. I have maintained a large network of individuals within the industry, so could easily build a team of 5-7 outstanding professionals from ground up for any product, project or assignment.

My future career goal is to become either an engineering manager or a line manager. While I am not seeking to move 100% away from technology, a 70/30 split of employee management and technology would be ideal for my skill set, with an emphasis on team creating, collaboration, motivation, making their job and thereby their life as motivated and fruitful as possible. I am also very open to relocation for the right position, as I greatly enjoy meeting new people, new experiences, and becoming acquainted with new cultures. I am easily adaptable and love new adventures.

# EDUCATION

College of Modern Business Studies (EDUTUS)
Marketing Communication (4 semesters- 2nd degree)

Academy of Communication (diploma certified by IAA)

Eötvös Loránd University (ELTE)

Computer Science- English Literature and Grammar

Neumann János Secondary School for Computer Technologies
IT technician qualification



https://www.edutus.hu/english/

https://www.iaaglobal.org/

https://www.elte.hu/en/





# COURSES

- Go Programming Course- Basics (40 hour classroom) (2023-)
- Certified Scrum Product Owner (scrumalliance.org) (2022-)
- ISTQB Test Manager course (40 hour classroom) (2022-)
- CSS3 with animation, grid and flex box training (30 hours online) (2021-)
- Vanilla javascript training (40 hours online) (2021-)
- Photoshop web design course (14 hours online) (2020-)
- React with redux course (50 hour online) (2020-)
- Docker and Kubernetes course (30 hours course by Igsoft-John Bryce) (2020-)
- Spring Rest course (40 hours course by Igsoft-John Bryce) (2019-)
- Software Architect course (30 hours course by Ericsson) (2018-)
- Group Dynamics, Team Lead course (50 hours by Group Dynamics) (2017-)
- Spring framework course (spring fw,springmvc,spring boot, 40 hours by Sprint consulting) (2017-).
- Scrum master course ( 24 hours by Sprint consulting) (2017-)
- Java 8 and Design Patterns Course (40 hours by Iqsoft-John Bryce) (2016-)
- Python basics course (40 hours by Iqsoft-John Bryce) (2015-)

### OTHER QUALIFICATIONS

- English Translator Certificate (Academical)
- Driving License "B" category

# 유를 SKILLS

- Test automation software: TestNG | Jbehave (BDD) | Cucumber | JUnit4 (TDD) | JUnit5 | Mockito | Selenium | jmeter | webmvctest | Cypress | Spring cloud contract | Rest Assured | Resttemplate | Postman | Mercury TestDirector | WinRunner | TestTrack | Testlink | QTP (Basic level)
- Programming skills: Java 7-8-9, Spring fw, Spring Boot, Spring Data, HTML5, CSS3, Sass, Javascript, Reactjs, Redux, Nextjs, jdbc, XML, Json, Real Basic, Visual Basic, PHP, Perl, Python (basics), WinRunner
  - DEVOPS: Jenkins, Docker, Sonar,
- **Build framework**: maven, gradle (basics)
- IDE: IntelliJ, Visual Studio Code, Eclipse, NetBeans
- Review: Collaborator, Gerrit
- SCM: Perforce, Git
- Database systems: MySQL
- Platforms: Windows, MacOS basics, Unix basics
- Software Development Process: Waterfall, Scaled Agile, Kanban
- Software Project management/other: OpenALM, JIRA, Rally, Power Point, Confluence, Word, Excel, OutLook
- Visual design softwares: Photoshop, Illustrator, Zbrush, Autodesk Maya, Adobe Premier, After Effects, ArchiCAD
- Leadership: six years experience of developing and implementing QA processes, and developing and leading software
  - QA projects and teams
- Software quality assurance: Nearly 19 years of experience as a software QA engineer, automating and executing test plans and test cases performing numerous types of testing (functional, acceptance, performance, regression); several years of experience managing software QA programs. Extensive experience writing, designing, implementing, managing, and executing automated testing in Java / WinRunner / Perl and implementing test frameworks with custom test aiding software solutions

### **PERSONALITY**

self-starter, pro-active, creative, efficient time-management and organizing skills, quick learner, team-player, loyal, high sense of responsibility, love to meet new people

#### HOBBY











photography











visual design





